<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">



<title type="text">The Random Ramblings of Christian Roberson</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/" />
<updated>2016-03-12T19:46:28-05:00</updated>
<id>/</id>
<author>
  <name>Christian Roberson</name>
  <uri>/</uri>
  <email>christian.roberson@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Website Reboot]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/misc/website-reborn"/>
  <id>/misc/website-reborn</id>
  <published>2016-03-12T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2016-03-12T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  
  <author>
    <name>Christian Roberson</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>christian.roberson@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <category scheme="/tags/#jekyll" term="jekyll" />
  <content type="html">
  
    &lt;p&gt;After some time away I am finally getting around to restarting my website and blog. My hope going forward is to fill it with posts about comptuer science, education, technical posts, and miscellaneous ramblings that may have no relevance to anything important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In its prior life this site was written using Wordpress. I thought about continuing to use Wordpress going forward, but ultimately decided on Github Pages and Jekyll. Here is why I made that decision:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Convenience&lt;/strong&gt;: Using Jekyll and Github pages fits in much better with my typical development workflow than using Wordpress does. I can run a local instance of Jekyll to work and make changes without publishing live on the site. It also lets me work on the site without needing an Internet connection. For example this post was mostly written while I was on a plane with no Wifi access. To publish updates simply requires a push to Github.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backups&lt;/strong&gt;: Because the site is maintained through a Github repository, everything is put in version control and stored on Github. This provides a version history and minimizes concern about lost data and work.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost Effective&lt;/strong&gt;: While my prior Wordpress site hosting wasn’t particularly expensive, it did add up over time. This solution is free (minus the cost of the domain name registration) and requires no long-term commitment or expense.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speed&lt;/strong&gt;: Since the site itself is essentially made up of static HTML pages and assests it is very fast and responsive. While Wordpress can be fairly responsive (depending on the theme) sometimes it can take a while to load a page.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am still learning how to take full advantage of Jekyll’s features, but so far I am quite enjoying it and its simplicity.&lt;/p&gt;

  
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/misc/website-reborn&quot;&gt;Website Reboot&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Christian Roberson at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;The Random Ramblings of Christian Roberson&lt;/a&gt; on March 12, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>
